#### Neha Satish

1913 Duffield Street, Ann Arbor, MI, 48109 770-756-4326 ~ nehasa1819@gmail.com

I'm a polyglot UMich computer science engineering student proficient in object-based programming and backend web development. My previous work experience was in the medical devices field, where I provided web dev support and marketing consulting. I am interested in gaining work experience in data analysis, UX design, machine learning, and any other areas that meld computing with other fields.

Languages: C++, Python, basic HTML and CSS, Java, currently working on C# Tools: Word, Excel, MS Project, Adobe Creative Cloud, SolidWorks, Linux Ubuntu, Git, Apache Hadoop

# **Experience:**

# **Computing:**

#### Girls Who Code

Johns Creek, GA

*May 2017-May 2019* 

Student/Club President

- Taught Python, HTML, CSS, Java
- Got students into full time post grad jobs at companies like Synchrony Financial (and other partners)

# **Coursera: Neural Networks and Deep Learning**

Johns Creek, GA

Student of deeplearning.ai

Sep 2018 - Oct 2018

- Backpropagation
- (Vectorized) Artificial Neural Networks
- Network Architecture

## **Coursera: Introduction to Big Data**

Johns Creek, GA

Student of UC San Diego

July 2018 - August 2108

- data collection, monitoring, storage, analysis and reporting
- core Hadoop stack components
  - o YARN resource
  - HDFS system
  - MapReduce model

# **Social Outreach/Legal Writing:**

## **Odyssey Online Writing Internship**

Johns Creek, GA

Social Media Manager/Intern

October 2016- February 2017

- Promoted others' articles as an editor to gain net traffic and advertize Odyssey as a brand
- Essential written communication skills

## Shafritz&Dean LLC. Internship

Suwanee, GA

Internship

August 2018- November 2019

- Filed water bills, taxes, and complete background checks on clients for state security
- Tested development of new file organization database

Debate Team Johns Creek, GA

Policy Debater

August 2013-May 2019

- Teamwork to analyze legal writing
- Advocated my argument regardless of external pressures or personal beliefs

Lincoln- Douglas Varsity Debater/2018 President

- Collaborated with team members to recruit, teach, and forge relations between teams from other schools
- Competed and judged in national tournaments

# **Biomedical:**

## **Health Occupations Students of America**

Johns Creek, GA

State Finalist / National Qualifier

August 2015

- Competed in Behavioral Health
- Psychologically analyzed the mindset of an individual and assess the motive of their actions

# Army Help Centre Personal Passion Project

Johns Creek, GA

May 2017-Present

On-Call Therapist

- Served as a therapist for people of all ages (usually around 12-30)
- Learned how to sympathize, empathize, and deal with life and death situations
- Social Media Management Skills (raised mental health awareness through booths, local TV, and projects with writers on Jungian theories)

## **Education:**

## University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Completing Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Engineering, 2023

## **Relevant Coursework:**

- EECS 203 Discrete Mathematics
  - Summary: propositional and predicate logic, set theory, functions and relations, growth of functions and asymptotic notation, elementary combinatorics, graph theory, and number theory.
- EECS 280 Programming and Introductory Data Structures
  - Summary: C++ Programming projects: Image processing program, Euchre, Web Backend, and Machine Learning Algorithms

**Northview High School** (4.0+ Final GPA)

## Links:

Coursera Certification:

https://coursera.org/share/1fe81529635b47fef36baaae86d1f214 https://coursera.org/share/bdc2ef3d2fef2bea252b1bc15dd92be0